Let's take a break from the theory and spend some time talking about TF records.
TF records are TensorFlow custom data format.
They are not necessarily required to train model with TensorFlow,
but may help when data loading becomes a bottleneck.
Also, the data in the Waymo Open Dataset is using the TFRecord format,
and you will be using that format for your final project.
Whereas XML or JSON format are human readable,
TF records files are not.
For example, let's try to open this TF record.
As you can see, this file is not human readable.
However, we can use protofiles to understand the structure of these TF records.
Let's look at an example of a protofile from the Waymo Open Dataset.
This protofile describes the structure of a TF record.
Well, from this profile,
I see that the TF record contains a field called CameraName,
which has the following six attributes; UNKOWN,
FRONT, FRONT_LEFT, FRONT_RIGHT, SIDE_LEFT, and SIDE_RIGHT.
Looking at this protofile is extremely informative,
and you will have to learn how to leverage them for the final project.
By the way, you can create TF records files from your own data format.
To do so, you will have to leverage a TensorFlow function called tf.train.Example.
You will learn about this in the next exercise.
Let's summarize what we have learned about TF records.
TF records are TensorFlow custom data formats.
They are not required to train a model with TensorFlow,
but they may help to speed up data loading.
Their structure is defined by protofiles.
TF records are created using protocol buffers or proto buff,
a mechanism to serialize data.